Guide to the Stanley Milgram Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Studies, 1927-1984; Series II
  - TV Violence
    - Study conditions
      - Telephone study: data analysis, Circa 1971 (Box 53, Folder 266)
    - Writings of others, references, Circa 1964-1973 (Box 53, Folder 267-269)
    - Writings of others, references, Circa 1954-1971 (Box 54, Folder 270-273)
- Writings, 1954-1993; Series III
  WRITINGS is organized in five sections: Published; Unpublished; Speeches; Films, completed; and Films, incomplete. Titles in the Published and Films, completed sections are listed in chronological order by date of publication or release, which is given in parentheses after the title. Speeches are listed in chronological order by date delivered. For each speech the title is given if known, followed by the place if known, with the date delivered in parentheses. In the sections for Unpublished and Films, incomplete, titles are listed in rough chronological order by project date. When there are several folders of material for a particular title, the material has been organized by record type and listed in alphabetical order.
  - Published
    - Le Journal de Victor Lyon (1958) (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Conformity in Norway and France (1960)
      - Thesis prospectus and summary, 1957-1958 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Thesis draft or fragments of draft, Undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Thesis, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Nationality and Conformity," Scientific American (1961)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Manuscript drafts, pre-1961 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Printed copy, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Printed copies, 1963, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - "Experiment at Yale," St. Louis Post-Dispatch (1963) (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - "Meaningful Tribute," Harvard Crimson (1963) (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - "Praise for the Health Center" (1963) (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - "Behavioral Study of Obedience," Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology (1963)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 55, Folder 14)
      - Printed copies, 1963, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - "Technique and First Findings of a Laboratory Study of Obedience to Authority," Yale Science Magazine (1964)
      - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 16)
      - Manuscript drafts in English and French, pre-1964 (Box 55, Folder 17)
      - Printed copy, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - "Paralyzed Witnesses: The Murder They Heard," Nation (1964) (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - "Issues in the Study of Obedience: A Reply to Baumrind," American Psychologist (1964)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 55, Folder 20)
      - Manuscript draft, pre-1964 (Box 55, Folder 21)
      - Printed copy, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - "Group Pressure and Action Against a Person," Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology (1964)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 56, Folder 23)
      - Requests, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 24)
      - Printed copy, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - "Liberating Effects of Group Pressure," Journal of Personality and Social Psychology (1965)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 56, Folder 26)
      - Printed copy, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - "Some Conditions of Obedience and Disobedience to Authority," Human Relations (1965)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 56, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, 1967, undated (Box 56, Folder 30)
      - Manuscript draft, English, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 31)
      - Manuscript draft, French, Undated (Box 56, Folder 32)
      - Manuscript draft, German, Pre-1966 (Box 56, Folder 33)
      - Printed copies, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 34)
      - Printed copies, 1966 (Box 56, Folder 35)
      - Printed copies, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 36)
      - Printed copies, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 37)
      - Printed copy, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 38)
    - "The Lost Letter Technique: A Tool of Social Science Research," Public Opinion Quarterly (1965) (Box 56, Folder 39)
    - "The Trunk of La Pergola," Alumni News (1966) (Box 56, Folder 40)
    - "Personality Characteristics Associated with Obedience and Defiance Toward Authoritative Command," Journal of Experimental Research in Personality (1966) (Box 56, Folder 41)
    - "Small World Problem," Psychology Today (1967)
      - Correspondence, 1967, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 42)
      - Drafts, Pre-1967 (Box 56, Folder 43)
      - Printed copy, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 44)
    - "Obedience to Criminal Orders: The Compulsion to Do Evil," Patterns of Prejudice (1967)
      - Buenos Aires discussion, Undated (Box 56, Folder 45)
      - Printed copies, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 46)
    - Sozialer Konformität," Wörterbuch der Soziologie (1969?), 1962-1963 (Box 57, Folder 47)
    - "Collective Behavior: Crowds and Social Movements," Revised Handbook of Social Psychology (1969)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 57, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 49)
      - Illustrations, Pre-1969 (Box 57, Folder 50)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1969 (Box 57, Folder 51)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1969 (Box 57, Folder 52)
      - Note cards, Pre-1969 (Box 57, Folder 53)
      - Note cards, Pre-1969 (Box 57, Folder 54)
      - Note cards, Pre-1969 (Box 57, Folder 55)
      - Note cards, Pre-1969 (Box 58, Folder 56)
      - Printed copies, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 57)
    - "Inter-disciplinary Thinking and the Small World Problem," Interdisciplinary Relationships in the Social Sciences (1969), Pre-1969 (Box 58, Folder 58)
    - "An Experimental Study of the Small World Problem," Sociometry (1969)
      - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 59)
      - Drafts, Pre-1969 (Box 58, Folder 60)
      - Drafts, Pre-1969 (Box 58, Folder 61)
      - Printed copy, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 62)
    - "The Lost Letter Technique," Psychology Today (1969)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 58, Folder 63)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1969 (Box 58, Folder 64)
      - Illustrations, 1963, 1966, undated (Box 58, Folder 65)
      - Printed copies, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 66)
    - "Comment on: A Failure to Validate the Lost Letter Technique," Public Opinion Quarterly (1969)
      - Notes, drafts, and correspondence, 1964, 1968, 1969, undated (Box 58, Folder 67)
      - Printed copy, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 68)
    - "Note on the Drawing Power of Crowds," Journal of Personality and Social Psychology (1969)
      - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 69)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1969 (Box 58, Folder 70)
      - Printed copy, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 71)
    - "Acquaintanceship Networks Between Racial Groups: Application of the Small World Method," Journal of Personality and Social Psychology (1970)
      - Draft and correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 58, Folder 72)
      - Printed copy, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 73)
    - "The Experience of Living in Cities," Science (1970)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 74)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1970 (Box 59, Folder 75)
      - Manuscript drafts, pre-1970 (Box 59, Folder 76)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1970 (Box 59, Folder 77)
      - Printed copies, 1970, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 78)
    - Review in The Nation of In the Service of Their Country: War Resisters in Prison (1970) (Box 59, Folder 79)
    - "Interpreting Obedience: Error and Evidence (A Reply to Orne and Holland)," The Social Psychology of the Psychological Experiment (1972)
      - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 80)
      - Drafts and fragments, Pre-1972 (Box 59, Folder 81)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1972 (Box 59, Folder 82)
      - Printed copies, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 83)
    - "Psychological Map of New York City," American Scientist (1972)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1972, undated (Box 59, Folder 84)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 85)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1972 (Box 59, Folder 86)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1972 (Box 59, Folder 87)
      - Illustrations, Pre-1972 (Box 60, Folder 88)
      - Printed copies, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 89)
    - "The Familiar Stranger: An Aspect of Urban Anonymity," Division 8 Newsletter (1972) (Box 60, Folder 90)
    - Essay review of "The Social Construction of Communities" in Science (1972) (Box 60, Folder 91)
    - "Introduction," Environment and Cognition (1973), 1971-1973 (Box 60, Folder 92)
    - Television and Antisocial Behavior (1973)
      - Correspondence and notes, 1972-1973, undated (Box 60, Folder 93)
      - Index, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 94)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 95)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 96)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 97)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 98)
      - Manuscript draft, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 99)
      - Manuscript draft, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 100)
      - Manuscript drafts and fragments, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 101)
      - Photographs and stills from film, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 102)
      - Promotion and reviews, 1974-1976, undated (Box 60, Folder 103)
      - Promotion and reviews, 1973, 1975, undated (Box 60, Folder 104)
      - Study materials, Pre-1973 (Box 60, Folder 105)
    - "The Perils of Obedience," Harper's (1973)
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 106)
      - Printed copy, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 107)
    - The Dogs of Pavlov (1973)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973, undated (Box 61, Folder 108)
      - Script, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 109)
    - Obedience to Authority: An Experimental View (1974)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 61, Folder 110)
      - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 111)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1977, undated (Box 61, Folder 112)
      - Correspondence: English publication, 1974-1975 (Box 61, Folder 113)
      - Distribution lists, Undated (Box 61, Folder 114)
      - Drafts and fragments: The Experiment and Its Variations, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 115)
      - Drafts and fragments: The Theory of Obedience, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 116)
      - Drafts and fragments: Theory of Obedience, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 117)
      - Drafts and fragments: Preliminary notions, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 118)
      - Drafts and fragments: Application of the Theory, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 119)
      - Drafts and fragments: Applying the Theory, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 120)
      - Drafts and fragments: Group Forces, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 121)
      - Drafts and fragments: Method of Inquiry; How the Study Was Done, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 122)
      - Drafts and fragments: outlines and introductory matter, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 123)
      - Drafts and fragments: The Dilemma of Obedience, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 124)
      - Drafts and fragments: The Individual Faces Authority, Pre-1974 (Box 61, Folder 125)
      - Drafts and fragments: Ethical Issues of the Experiment, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 126)
      - Drafts and fragments: Ethical Issues of the Experiment, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 127)
      - Drafts and fragments: Problems of the Method, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 128)
      - Drafts and fragments: Obedience in Modern Experience, Future of Obedience, Epilogue, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 129)
      - Drafts and fragments: Obedience in Modern Experience, Future of Obedience, Epilogue, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 130)
      - Drafts and fragments: Obedience in Modern Experience, Future of Obedience, Epilogue, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 131)
      - Drafts and fragments: references, Pre-1974 (Box 62, Folder 132)
      - Drafts: chapters 1-3, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 133)
      - Drafts: chapters 4-6, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 134)
      - Drafts: chapters 7-8, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 135)
      - Drafts: chapters 9-10, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 136)
      - Drafts: chapters 11-12, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 137)
      - Drafts: pages 1-64, 1972 (Box 63, Folder 138)
      - Drafts: pages 65-139, 1972 (Box 63, Folder 139)
      - Drafts: pages 140-218, 1972 (Box 63, Folder 140)
      - Drafts: pages 219-end, 1972 (Box 63, Folder 141)
      - Illustrations, Pre-1974 (Box 63, Folder 142)
        See also: box 145, folder 12
      - Jacket material, Pre-1974 (Box 63, Folder 143)
      - Page proofs, Pre-1974 (Box 63, Folder 144)
      - Promotional appearances, 1973-1974 (Box 63, Folder 145)
      - Promotional statements, 1974, undated (Box 63, Folder 146)
      - Publicity, 1973-1974 (Box 63, Folder 147)
      - Reviews, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 148)
      - Reviews, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 149)
      - Reviews, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 150)
      - Reviews, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 151)
      - Reviews, Undated (Box 63, Folder 152)
      - Reviews, English, 1974-1975, undated (Box 64, Folder 153)
      - Reviews, French, 1975, 1979, undated (Box 64, Folder 154)
      - Reviews, German, 1974, undated (Box 64, Folder 155)
    - "We Are All Obedient," The Listener (1974)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1974 (Box 64, Folder 156)
      - Printed copies, 1974 (Box 64, Folder 157)
    - "The Image Freezing Machine," ASMP Journal of Photography (1975)
      - Correspondence, 1976, 1977, undated (Box 64, Folder 158)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1975 (Box 64, Folder 159)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1975 (Box 64, Folder 160)
      - Printed copies, 1975-1977 (Box 64, Folder 161)
      - Printed copies, 1978, undated (Box 64, Folder 162)
    - "The Tenth Level" (1976)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1976, undated (Box 64, Folder 163)
      - Fragments, Circa 1975 (Box 64, Folder 164)
    - Psychology in Today's World (1975)
      - Correspondence and notes, 1974-1976 (Box 64, Folder 165)
      - Drafts, Undated (Box 64, Folder 166)
    - Galerie Gerald Piltzer exhibit: "Paris Psychologique" (1975)
      - Contact prints, Circa 1975 (Box 64, Folder 167)
      - Correspondence and notes, 1974-1976, undated (Box 64, Folder 168)
      - Exhibit catalogue, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 169)
      - Negatives, Circa 1975 (Box 64, Folder 170)
        See also: box 145, folder 13
      - Photographs, Circa 1975 (Box 64, Folder 171)
        See also: box 145, folder 14
    - "Psychological Maps of Paris," Environmental Psychology: People and Their Physical Settings (1976)
      - Manuscript drafts, Circa 1973 (Box 65, Folder 172)
      - Manuscripts drafts, Circa 1973 (Box 65, Folder 173)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1976, undated (Box 65, Folder 174)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1976 (Box 65, Folder 175)
      - Manuscript drafts; tables; illustrations, Pre-1976 (Box 65, Folder 176)
      - Report, Pre-1976 (Box 65, Folder 177)
      - Printed copies, 1976-1977 (Box 65, Folder 178)
    - "City Families," Psychology Today (1977)
      - Correspondence, 1977, undated (Box 65, Folder 179)
      - Manuscript drafts and printed copy, 1977, undated (Box 65, Folder 180)
    - "The Social Meaning of Fanaticism," Etcetera (1977), 1976, undated (Box 65, Folder 181)
    - "Subject Reaction: The Neglected Factor in the Ethics of Experimentation," Hastings Center Report (1977)
      - Correspondence and manuscript drafts, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 182)
      - Printed copies, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 183)
    - "Reflections on News," Antioch Review (1977), 1977, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 184)
    - The Individual in a Social World, Essays and Experiments (1977)
      - Conceptual outlines, 1976, undated (Box 65, Folder 185)
      - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 65, Folder 186)
      - Drafts: Preface and Acknowledgments, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 187)
      - Drafts: Introduction, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 188)
      - Drafts: Obedience, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 189)
      - Drafts: The Individual and Authority, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 190)
      - Drafts: The Individual and the Group, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 191)
      - Drafts: The Individual in the City, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 192)
      - Drafts: The Individual in a Communicative Web, Pre-1977 (Box 65, Folder 193)
      - Drafts: references, Pre-1977 (Box 66, Folder 194)
      - Drafts: Milgram's biography, Pre-1977 (Box 66, Folder 195)
      - Drafts and fragments, Pre-1977 (Box 66, Folder 196)
      - Drafts and fragments, Pre-1977 (Box 66, Folder 197)
      - Drafts: part 1, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 198)
      - Drafts: part 2, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 199)
      - Drafts: part 3, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 200)
      - Drafts: part 4, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 201)
      - Illustrations, Pre-1977 (Box 66, Folder 202)
        See also: box 145, folder 15
      - Permissions, Pre-1977 (Box 66, Folder 203)
    - "On Maintaining Social Norms: A Field Experiment in the Subway," Advances in Environmental Psychology (1978)
      - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 66, Folder 204)
      - Drafts and printed copies, 1978 (Box 66, Folder 205)
    - "A Work of Great Potential Influence," Contemporary Psychology (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 66, Folder 206)
    - "Who Joins the Unions: A Survey of Research," The Clarion (1978) (Box 66, Folder 207)
    - "Candid Camera," Society (1979)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1979, undated (Box 66, Folder 208)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 209)
      - Printed copies, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 210)
      - Proofing audio tape, Circa 1979 (Box 66, Folder 211)
    - "Préface à la deuxieme edition française," Soumission à l'Autorité (1979)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 212)
      - Printed copies, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 213)
    - "Experimental projects in the Psychology of Photography," Artes Visuales (1980), 1980-1981, undated (Box 67, Folder 214)
    - Instructor's Manual for the Book Obedience to Authority (1980)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1980 (Box 67, Folder 215-217)
      - Printed copies, 1980 (Box 67, Folder 218)
    - Commentary on "This Week's Citation Classic 'Behavioral Study of Obedience'," Current Contents (1981) (Box 67, Folder 219)
    - "Teaching About Obedience," High School Psychology Teacher (1981)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 67, Folder 220)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 221)
      - Printed copy, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 222)
    - "Understanding Psychological Man: A State-of-the-Science Report," Psychology Today (1982) (Box 67, Folder 223)
    - "Reflections on Morelli's 'Dilemma of Obedience'," Metaphilosophy (1983) (Box 67, Folder 224)
    - "Resolving Conflicts Among Individuals Who Share an Environment, Perspectives on Adaptation, Environment and Population (1983)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 67, Folder 225)
      - Manuscript draft and fragments, Circa 1977 (Box 67, Folder 226)
      - Printed copy, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 227)
    - "The Vertical City," CUNY Graduate School Magazine (1984)
      - Drafts, notes and correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 67, Folder 228)
      - Printed copies, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 229)
    - "Psychology of Computer Networking," Omni (1984) (Box 67, Folder 230)
    - "A Patient's View of the Hospital Strike," Riverdale Press (1984) (Box 67, Folder 231)
    - "Cities as Social Representations," Social Representations (1984)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 67, Folder 232)
      - Correspondence, 1983, undated (Box 67, Folder 233)
      - Drafts and notes, 1978, pre-1983 (Box 67, Folder 234)
      - Manuscript drafts, Pre-1983 (Box 67, Folder 235)
      - Printed copy, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 236)
    - "Obedience," Encyclopedia of Psychology (1984), 1982-1983, undated (Box 68, Folder 237)
    - "The Role of the Self in Biological and Cultural Systems: A Response to Czikszentmihalyi and Massimini," New Ideas in Psychology (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 68, Folder 238)
    - "Response to Intrusion into Waiting Lines ," Journal of Personality and Social Psychology (1986)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1985, undated (Box 68, Folder 239)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1982, pre-1986 (Box 68, Folder 240-243)
      - Notes, Pre-1986 (Box 68, Folder 244)
      - Printed copy, 1986 (Box 68, Folder 245)
    - "Obedience," Oxford Companion to the Mind (1987?)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 68, Folder 246)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 247)
  - Unpublished
    - The French Press and the German Occupation, 1940-1944, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 248)
    - Stereotypes, 1955-1957 (Box 68, Folder 248a)
    - National Character, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 249)
    - NY Times article: Obedience theory, Circa 1964 (Box 68, Folder 240)
    - Laughter Under stress, Circa 1966 (Box 68, Folder 251)
    - Inter-Disciplinary Thinking and the Small World Problem: correspondence and paper, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 252)
    - Review of Contemporary Japanese Prints by M. Kawakita
      - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 69, Folder 253)
      - Drafts and final version, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 254)
    - Experimental Study of the Postal System: correspondence and final draft, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 255)
    - Time Discrepancy Between Right Eye and Left Eye Vision, Circa 1967 (Box 69, Folder 256)
    - The Dilemma of Obedience, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 257)
    - Grandparents, Circa 1973 (Box 69, Folder 258)
    - Psychology Text, Circa 1973 (Box 69, Folder 259)
    - Human Behavior: an Introduction to Psychology
      - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 260-261)
      - Drafts, Circa 1976 (Box 69, Folder 262)
      - Notes, Circa 1976 (Box 69, Folder 263)
      - Outlines, Circa 1976 (Box 69, Folder 264)
    - Social Influence on Judgement and Decision Making
      - Curriculum project, Circa 1974- 1976 (Box 69, Folder 265)
      - Curriculum project: drafts, Undated (Box 69, Folder 266)
      - Student manual: working draft, Undated (Box 69, Folder 267)
      - Teachers manual: working draft, Undated (Box 70, Folder 268)
    - Photography as a Human Activity
      - Correspondence, 1975-1978, undated (Box 70, Folder 269)
      - Interim drafts, Undated (Box 70, Folder 270)
      - Manuscript draft, Undated (Box 70, Folder 271)
      - Manuscript draft, Circa 1977 (Box 70, Folder 272)
        See also: box 145, folder 16
      - Notes, Circa 1977 (Box 70, Folder 273)
    - Social Psychology: An Interpretation, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 274)
      - Reference articles volume, Circa 1977
        See: box 145, folder 17
    - Cyranoid - Wiley Encyclopedia, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 275)
    - Communities with Violence-Free Television, Undated (Box 70, Folder 276)
    - Conformity Book: draft, Undated (Box 70, Folder 277)
    - Connotations and Common English Given Names, Undated (Box 70, Folder 278)
    - Designing an Eye, Undated (Box 70, Folder 279)
    - German Leaders and German Followers: An Essay, Undated (Box 70, Folder 280)
    - Inertial Systems in Social Behavior, Undated (Box 70, Folder 281)
    - Photography and Behavior: manuscript drafts, Undated (Box 70, Folder 282)
    - The Reactions of Subjects to an Experiment Involving Social Illusion, Undated (Box 70, Folder 283)
    - Social Intrusion, Undated (Box 70, Folder 284)
    - The Study of Obedience and Its Critics, Undated (Box 70, Folder 285)
    - Theory of Social Issues, Undated (Box 70, Folder 286)
    - Toward the Reduction of Artifact in Socio-Psychological Experiments, Undated (Box 70, Folder 287)
    - War and Social Psychology: drafts and notes, Undated (Box 70, Folder 288)
    - Obedience fragments, Undated (Box 70, Folder 289)
    - Obedience fragments, Undated (Box 70, Folder 290)
    - Obedience fragments, Undated (Box 70, Folder 291)
    - Unidentified fragments, Undated (Box 71, Folder 292)
    - Unidentified fragments, Undated (Box 71, Folder 293)
  - Speeches
    - New Haven Shrine Club (1961 Oct 6), 1961 October 6 (Box 71, Folder 294)
    - Hudson Institute (1962 Nov 19), 1962 November (Box 71, Folder 295)
    - Obedience, Yale Hillel (1962 Nov 30), 1962 November 30 (Box 71, Folder 296)
    - Obedience, Columbia University (1964 Mar 26), 1963-1964 (Box 71, Folder 297)
    - Images and Crowds in the Presidential Election, Voice of America (1964 Oct 4), 1964 October 4 (Box 71, Folder 298)
    - A Choice is Made: audio tape (1964 Oct 26), 1964 October 26 (Box 71, Folder 299)